<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Type</title>
    <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Web Type</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>WEB TYPE (RISD GRAPH-2313-01) 3 credits Marie Otsuka (motsuka@risd.edu)  This course explores typography within the browser, considering the web not as a container but as a medium. We will develop typography that activates the capacities and conditions of websites. Projects will first respond our local browser conditions and different device environments, then expand to working with the remote network as source material. Critique and discussions will examine how publishing on the internet entails a distinct form of engagement and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various types of sites</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/links/</guid>
      <description>Below are links to webtype-type sites. The purpose here is to document a variety of web/type use rather than to showcase exemplary samples of content or aesthetics.
Reading collections  The Avery Review HTML Output Critical Atlas of the Internet Justin McGuirk Poetic Computation Untold Stories Wendy36  Typographic web designs  Illuminating Radioactivity XXXI XXXI Intro to Coding Workshop Nathan Tokyo Z-Bau Typeforce Wattis Institute Shiraz Abdullahi Gallab: Headgear Synoptic Office: Chinese Type Archive Russian Type journal Dowse Museum Stedlijk Strelka Alumni Ball Het Nieuwe Institut PACKET Index Art Book Fair Kurimanzutto  Sites for Typefaces  Fem Type Untitled Sans Hypertext Google Fonts and Chinese Google Fonts and Korean Temporary State Alfatype Gimlet IBM Plex Recursive  Type as Form  Sweethearts Elswewhere Data Patterns Monomono studio YES YES YES Moonsick Gang  Interactive Text  place a stone clickclickclick 2013 Lisbon Architecture Triennale  Generators  Hello from Here Space Type Generator Letters from Sweden: Funkis ABC Metaflop Universal Sans  Type and Audio  Secousse Radio Laurel Halo Truth and Quantity Goertek Phase  Online Publications  Rhizome Triple Canopy Triple Canopy: The Binder and the Server E-flux The New Inquiry Rachel Rosenfelt: The New Inquiry The Intercept The Creative Independent Dan Michaelson / Jack Balkin: Sometimes it looks like a duck, sometimes it looks like a rabbit  Web Design Studios  Linked by Air Rumors Studio Studio Moniker Project Projects  General Website Collections  Hoverstates Hallo Internet Brutalist Websites Readymag  Classics  Rafael Rozendaal Jodi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colophon</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/colophon/</guid>
      <description>This site is a work-in-progress. The website will evolve as we progress through our class — you can inspect its code and use it as a tool to learn the techniques discussed in class.
 Full code for this site is available on Github It is compiled with the static site generator Hugo  V5 April 9
 add print styles via media queries  V4 March 12
 add “dark mode” button via jQuery  V3 March 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Management Systems</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/09-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/09-cms/</guid>
      <description>aesthetics and governance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/projects/collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/projects/collection/</guid>
      <description>Documentation Develop a single webpage that provides a link to each project you’ve completed this semester. This index page will serve as a homepage for this class. You might also include exercises or alternate drafts that you experimented before developing the final version of your website. As you organize / reorganize your Github repository, make sure to double check that all links, including assets such as fonts and images, are properly linked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Editorial</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/projects/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/projects/project4/</guid>
      <description>The next phase is our final project — the goal is to engage in editorial design on the web, developing a collection of texts as as a publication. Below are several directions on how you might go about doing this.
General requirements:
 Typeset at least 12 longform articles Design at least 2 types of article layouts, in addition to the homepage Consider what kind of viewing modes are available for Consider the relationship between images &amp;amp; words Experiment with how we navigate from one article to another Develop a robust typographic identity system, paying careful attention to typographic hierarchy and refinements  a) Web Publication / Anthology Consider a current area of research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery and JSON</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/08-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/08-jquery/</guid>
      <description>Objects in JavaScript</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/07-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/07-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Writing instructions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letterforms over time</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/06-digital-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/06-digital-type/</guid>
      <description>How we came to variable fonts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change over time</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/05-variation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/05-variation/</guid>
      <description>CSS transitions and animations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type Design Basics</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/04-typedesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/04-typedesign/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Terminology and Glyphs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2 &amp; 3: Typeface as a Medium</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/projects/project2-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/projects/project2-3/</guid>
      <description>“But in any context, large or small, designing the medium is managing the potentials and relationships between objects, the activity or disposition immanent in their organization.” – Keller Eastering
 Reading  Keller Easterling: Medium Design (Excerpt) Typotheque: Typeface as Programme  Project 2 Create a variable font, considering the axes of variation as a medium. With this format, you are not only designing the visual instances of letterforms — you are designing the relationship with the typographer (or anyone who uses the font.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5Es Experience Framework</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/experience-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/experience-framework/</guid>
      <description>The “5Es of Experience Design” provides a framework to curate and design experiential work. It helps us consider some guiding questions:
 How would you like people to move through the experience? How can you attract them and keep them engaged?   Entice  How are visitors invited to participate? How are they invited to the space in the first place?   Enter  What is the threshold moment where a visitor transitions from their world to yours?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Layouts and Structure</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/03-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/03-layouts/</guid>
      <description>Positioning, layouts, and responsive design</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Basics</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/02-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/02-css/</guid>
      <description>Basic syntax, inheritance, the cascade, and selectors</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/01-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/01-html/</guid>
      <description>Semantic markup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Website as ?</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/projects/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/projects/project1/</guid>
      <description>“My favorite aspect of websites is their duality: they’re both subject and object at once. In other words, a website creator becomes both author and architect simultaneously. There are endless possibilities as to what a website could be. What kind of room is a website? Or is a website more like a house? A boat? A cloud? A garden? A puddle? Whatever it is, there’s potential for a self-reflexive feedback loop: when you put energy into a website, in turn the website helps form your own identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Type: Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/00-webtype/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/lectures/00-webtype/</guid>
      <description>This course is purposely named with shortened, less precise versions the words “web” and “type” to broaden our perspective on our explorations.
Web could refer to websites, but also to the web infrastructure, to the technology and culture of the world wide web; the protocols that compose the fabric of our internet; the act of weaving a web.
Type could refer to typography — the arrangement of letterforms — but also typefaces themselves, the quality of letterforms; to type, the act of typing, or writing, or coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Errors</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/common-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/common-errors/</guid>
      <description>Common errors to watch out for when troubleshooting:
HTML  Are your HTML elements wrapped in open and close tags? Are your HTML elements properly nested? Do your attribute values have quotation marks around them? Are your directory paths correct? Double check your link syntax.  CSS  Do you have opening and closing brackets? Does your property and value pairs have colons in between them? Do you have a semicolon at the end of each declaration?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type Help</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/type-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/type-help/</guid>
      <description>Below are links to some resources for typefaces and typography.
Webfont distributors  Any foundry website Adobe Fonts Google Web Fonts  Should you self-host Google Fonts?    Open Source  Open Foundry Future Fonts Use &amp;amp; Modify Libre Fonts by Womxn Velvetyne Collletttivo OSP Kitchen League of Movable Type Font Squirrel and webfont generator  Typography Reference  Matthew Butterick’s Practical Typography Typewolf Ellen Lupton&amp;rsquo;s Thinking with Type  Foundry Websites  Occupant Fonts Commercial Type Showcase Colophon Foundry Klim Type Grilli Type Ohno Type Sharp Type DJR Vocal Type Frere-Jones Type  Type technology tools and reference  Using @font-face A Variable Fonts Primer typetura.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Help</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/web-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/web-help/</guid>
      <description>Below are links to some resources for coding.
Documentation  Mozilla Developer Network Devdocs  Guides  What is a URL? Folder Poetry Dealing with files What goes in your head Why Coding Style Matters on Smashing Magazine (with useful list of validators) Writing your Best Code: HTML/CSS coding best practices and list of resources Google developer documentation style guide Sublime Text unofficial documentation &amp;amp; keyboard shortcuts  HTML  About Semantic HTML elements Overview of newer HTML tags Mix Blend Mode Nth-Child Paragraph Formatting on the Web Character sets: HTML Entities and Character Codes  CSS  CSS inheritance Shay Howe&amp;rsquo;s Guides CSS Basics Codecademy A guide to centering things Layout tutorials CSS Tricks Simple Grid Approach Articles on A List Apart: Content-out Layout | The Infinite Grid | Fluid Grids Using Style Tiles  Media Queries &amp;amp; Responsive design  Responsive Web Design Responsive Design Media Queries 7 Habits of Highly Effective Media Queries mediaqueri.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Terms</title>
      <link>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/html-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://risd-web.github.io/webtype-spring2020/resources/html-terms/</guid>
      <description>Tag: a tag is used for creating an element, which consists of the name of an HTML element in angle brackets. (i.e. &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; for paragraph.)
  Element: An element is a part of a webpage. A typical element includes an opening tag with some attributes, enclosed text content, and a closing tag. (i.e. &amp;lt;h1 class=&amp;quot;news&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Heading &amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;)
  Attribute: An attribute extends a tag, changing its behavior or providing metadata.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>